You just can't stand to be on your own!
貴様は孤独に耐えられなかっただけだ
Who isn't alone in this society?
この社会に孤独でない人間など誰がいる
There's no place for communities in this world
誰もがシステムに見守られ
where everyone is watched over by the
system and lives within the system's standards.
システムの規範に沿って生きる世界には
人の輪なんて必要ない
Everyone stays in their own little cell,
みんな 小さな独房の中で
and the system tames them by giving
them each their own personal serenity.
自分だけの安らぎに飼いならされているだけだ
You're the same too, right, Kougami Shinya?
君だってそうだろ 狡噛慎也
No one accepted your justice.
誰も君の正義を認めなかった
No one understood your anger, either.
君の怒りを理解しなかった
So you turned your back on trust and friendships,
だから君は信頼にも友情にも背を向けて
and you even abandoned the only place
you could belong to in order to come this far.
たった一つ 自分に残された居場所さえかなぐり捨てて
ここまで来た
And yet you laugh at my solitude?
そんな君が僕の孤独を笑うのか
But, you know, I highly value one who doesn't fear solitude—
だがね…僕はむしろ評価する
孤独を恐れない者を
you, who turned your solitude into a weapon.
孤独を武器にしてきた君を
#22: Perfect World
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
Look into my head
I don't know why I'm so harsh
I don’t
know why I’m so harsh
I could be so brash
I'm going to clash
I’m going to clash
'Cause I feel
’cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear, lend my ear
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
voices inside
One link to join it all again
one link to join it all
Again
'Cause I feel
’cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear, lend my ear
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
voices inside
One link to join it all
one link to join it all
So it goes again
so it goes again
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:死树懒  校对:西西    时间轴:Maize     压制：娜夏
You never learn, do you, Kougami?
お前は成長がないな…狡噛
Hold it right there,
そこまでです
Kougami.
狡噛さん…
Please don't move.
動かないでください
Makishima is nearby.
槙島もすぐそばにいるぞ
Yes, I know. I'll apprehend him too.
分かってます
あの男も捕まえます
Are you going to handcuff me here and go after him all by yourself?
ここで俺にワッパをかけて
後はあんた一人で槙島を追う気か
I'm not that reckless.
そこまで無謀じゃありませんよ 私
This is locked in Paralyzer mode with the safety off.
セーフティーは解除されたままで
パラライザーで固定されてます
You should be able to use it too.
今のあなたにも使えるはずです
Please help me catch him.
手伝ってください
We'll use the Paralyzer on Makishima. Nothing more.
槙島は パラライザーで麻痺させるだけ
If you try anything beyond that, I'll shoot you in the leg.
それ以上のことをしようとしたら
私はあなたの足を撃ちます
I'm surprised.
驚いたね
Well, I'm not surprised to see you toughen up.
タフになると思っちゃいたが…
But you could stand to be a bit nicer about it.
まだもう少し可愛げがあってもよかったと思うぜ
Why are you so focused on making sure nobody kills Makishima?
あんたがどうあっても 槙島を殺さないのは…
Because it's illegal.
違法だからです
Because I can't overlook a crime.
犯罪を見過ごせないからです
Why are you going that far to obey the law
悪人を裁けず
人を守れない法律を
when that law can neither judge a criminal nor protect people?
何でそうまでして守り通そうとするんだ
The law doesn't protect people.
法が人を守るんじゃない
People protect the law.
人が法を守るんです
People have always detested evil
and sought out a righteous way of living.
これまで 悪を憎んで
正しい生き方を探し求めてきた人々の思いが…
The law is the accumulation of those people's feelings.
その積み重ねが法なんです
They're neither the provisions nor the system.
それは 条文でもシステムでもない
They're the fragile and irreplaceable
feelings that everyone carries in their hearts.
誰もが心の中に抱えてる
脆くて掛け替えのない思いです
Compared to the power of anger and hatred,
怒りや憎しみの力に比べたら
they are something that can quite easily break down.
どうしようもなく簡単に壊れてしまうものなんです
All throughout time, people have prayed for a better world.
だから より良い世界を創ろうとした過去全ての人たちの祈りを
In order for those prayers to continue to hold meaning,
無意味にしてしまわないために…
we have to try our best to protect it to the very end.
それは最後まで 頑張って守り通さなきゃいけないんです
We can't just give up on it.
諦めちゃいけないんです
If there ever comes a time when everyone feels that way,
いつか
誰もがそう思うような時代が来れば…
the Sibyl System will probably disappear.
その時はシビュラシステムなんて消えちまうだろう
There'll no longer be any latent criminals or Enforcers.
潜在犯も 執行官もいなくなるだろう
But...
だが…
Tsk!
Akane!
朱
I wish...
いい加減
you guys would stop insulting us...
僕たちを侮辱するのは…
already.
止めてほしい
I see...
そうか…
You are...
君は…
N-No...
だ…駄目…
This is between the two of us.
これは 俺とあいつだけの問題なんだ
Kougami!
狡噛さーん！
Everyone is alone.
誰だって孤独だ
Everyone is empty.
誰だって虚ろだ
People no longer have any need of others.
もう 誰も他人を必要としない
You can always find a substitute for any talent.
どんな才能も
スペアが見つかる
Any relationship can be replaced.
どんな関係でも取り換えが利く
That's the world I grew tired of.
そんな世界に
飽きていた
And yet, for some reason...
でも どうしてかな
I can't even imagine someone else besides you killing me.
僕が君以外の誰かに殺される光景は…
どうしても 思い浮かばないんだ
Say, what do you think, Kougami?
なあ どうなんだ
狡噛
After all this is done, will you be able to find a replacement for me?
君はこの後 僕の代わりを見つけられるのか
Sorry, but I hope I never do.
いいや
もう二度とごめんだね
This destiny must have awaited them since long before they had even met.
二人は
初めて出会うより以前から…
ああなる運命だったんだろう
They were not like mere ships passing in the night.
すれ違っていたわけでもない
It was not like they didn't understand each other.
分かり合えなかったわけでもない
They understood each other better than anyone else,
彼らは誰よりもお互いを理解し…
and each was focused solely on the other.
相手のことだけを見詰めていた…
Kougami...
狡噛さん…
The outcome of the attempt to capture
Makishima Shougo was quite regrettable.
槙島聖護の身柄確保については
大変遺憾な結果となりました
Does that mean I'm no longer needed?
これで私は用済みってこと
We have no choice but to
downgrade our assessment of your abilities.
常守朱の能力評価については
下方修正を余儀なくされます
However, that does not mean that you possess a negative net worth.
…が それによって
あなたの存在価値がマイナスに転じるわけではありません
Rather, you are still an individual of outstanding
value with regards to managing the Sibyl System.
むしろシビュラシステムの運営上
あなたは依然として 特出した価値を持つ個人です
What do you mean?
どういう意味よ
You have a healthy, strong Psycho-Pass,
あなたの健康かつ強靱なサイコパスと
as well as a clear mind and judgment.
明晰な頭脳 判断力は来たるべき新たな時代の市民に示す指標として
We can say that your qualities are as close to ideal as they come
for serving as an example to the citizens of the coming new era.
十分な理想型といえます
Furthermore, you hold an emotional antipathy that is
completely contrary to your theoretical assessment of the Sibyl System,
そして あなたはシビュラシステムに対し
完全に相反する感情的反感と理論的評価を抱いており
and that conflict continues to exist.
今なおその葛藤は継続している
If we can establish a means of winning you over to our side,
そんなあなたを懐柔する手法が確立できたなら
we will be able to obtain valuable sample data
for taking the governance of society to the next level.
我々は 社会の統制を次の段階に進める上で
貴重なサンプルデータを獲得できることでしょう
What are you up to?
何を企んでいるの
The true form of the Sibyl System is currently
kept secret out of consideration for public opinion.
目下のところ 世論の情勢を鑑みて
シビュラシステムの実体は
完全に秘匿されています
However, such obfuscation is
nothing but a simple, short-term strategy.
短期的戦略としての隠蔽工作は 現状ではまだ容易ですが
In the long term, this course of action is not desirable.
長期的視野に立った場合
これは決して望ましい方針ではない
We should eventually make the truth public.
いずれ我々は 偽らざる姿を公のものとするべきなのです
If we can create an environment where every
citizen still enjoys and accepts our governance
全ての市民がシビュラの正体を認識し 了解した上で
after they are made aware of our true form,
我々による統制を享受するようになる環境を整えること
such an achievement will solidify the
stability and prosperity of the future human society.
この課題の達成は
将来の人類社会に
より盤石な安定と繁栄をもたらすことでしょう
Continuing to observe and analyze your movements
我々が引き続きあなたの動向を観察し 解析することは
will provide us with valuable hints on how to build a methodology
未来の市民を懐柔し 順応させる方法論を構築する
for winning over the citizens in the future and getting them to adapt.
貴重な手掛かりとなるのです
You think it'll all go as smoothly as that?
そんなにうまくいくと思ってるの
As long as you refrain from
jeopardizing the secrecy of this information,
機密保守を脅かす兆候がないかぎり
your life and your freedom of action will be guaranteed.
あなたの生命と行動の自由は保障されるでしょう
We hope you will cooperate with us.
協力的態度を期待します
If you wish to follow your own drive for
self-preservation, there is only one choice.
自己保存の欲求に従えば
あなたに選択の余地はないはずです
You're right. I don't want to die in vain,
そうね
犬死にはごめんだし
and it's true that the current society cannot hold without Sibyl.
今の世の中がシビュラ抜きでは成り立たないのも事実だし
We feel that we can trust in your
respect for the law when you make decisions.
あなたの順法精神に基づく判断は信頼に値します
Do you know the most demeaning thing
you can do to the law that we should respect?
尊くあるべきはずの法を
何よりも貶めることは何だか 分かってる
Creating and administering a law that is unworthy of protection.
それはね
守るに値しない法律をつくり 運用することよ
You shouldn't underestimate humans.
人間を甘く見ないことね
We're always aiming for a better society.
私たちはいつだって
より良い社会を目指してる
One day, someone will come to this room to turn off the power.
いつか誰かがこの部屋の電源を落としにやって来るわ
We will find a new path. You can count on it.
きっと新しい道を見つけてみせる
There is no place for the Sibyl System in our future!
シビュラシステム
あなたたちに未来なんてないのよ
Tsunemori Akane...
常守朱
Fight.
抗いなさい
Struggle.
苦悩しなさい
So that it may lead us to evolve.
我々に進化をもたらす糧として…
2 months later
Hey, it's been a while.
やあ 久しぶり…
I came to talk to you today,
今日は報告に来た
since I've decided what I'm going to do next.
身の振り方を決めたんでね
My Crime Coefficient went up to 140.
犯罪係数
１４０までいったよ
There's no longer any chance of recovery.
もう回復の見込みはない
But it's not in my nature to sit
around and mope in an isolation facility.
だが 隔離施設で腐ってるのも性に合わなくてね…
So I decided to go back to where I used to work.
結局 古巣に戻ることにした
You told me to take a different path.
違う道を進めとあんたは言ったが
Guess I didn't live up to your expectations.
ご期待には添えなかったわけだ
I ended up being a terrible son in every way, didn't I?
どこまでも 親不孝な息子だよ
But strangely enough, I don't have any regrets.
でもな 不思議と後悔はしてないんだ
There's nothing good about being a detective.
デカなんて碌なもんじゃない
But it's a job that someone needs to do.
それでも
誰かが引き受けなきゃならない仕事だ
Right... Dad?
そうだろ
親父
Sorry to drag you out here.
手間をかけさせてすまない
That's okay. It's my duty to
accompany Enforcers when they go outside.
いえ 執行官の外出に同伴するのは
服務規程ですから
Unlike Kagari, at least my dad was able to get a proper grave.
ああして墓があるだけ 縢よりはましだ
Division 2 was told to give up their investigation on him, right?
二係の調査 打ち切られたんだろ
Yeah.
ええ
I don't think Kagari is alive.
きっと縢は もうこの世にいない
I'm sure the top brass found evidence of that,
上層部はその確証をつかんだ上で
but they're trying to sweep it under the rug and keep it from the public.
発表せずにうやむやにしてる
I wonder where Kougami is.
狡噛さんは どこにいるんでしょうね
When the collar comes off such a wild hunting dog,
あれだけ獰猛な猟犬から首輪が外れたら
he becomes no different from a wolf.
それはもうオオカミと変わらない
Now that he's back in the wild,
むしろ野生に戻った分
maybe he's living a comparatively free and easygoing life.
伸び伸びとやってるかもしれん
Would his life really be all that relaxing?
そんな…気楽なものでしょうか
It's not like he took it easy as an Enforcer, right?
執行官だったころのあいつが
気楽にやってたわけでもないだろう
He was a perseverant, cunning
man who didn't know when to give up.
しぶとくて 狡猾で
諦めの悪い男だった
No matter how bad the situation, he'll always pull through.
どんな過酷な状況だろうと あいつはきっと切り抜ける
If anything, I'm more concerned about you, Inspector Tsunemori.
むしろ心配なのは 常守監視官
あなたの方だ
What? Me?
えっ…私
You're ever the worrier, Ginoza.
相変わらず心配性ですね 宜野座さんは…
Let's look at the future, rather than the past.
過去よりも未来に目を向けよう
A new Inspector will be assigned tomorrow, right?
新任の監視官
明日には着任するんだろう
It's unusual to hire a minor, isn't it?
異例の人事ですよね
未成年の登用なんて…
We're partially responsible for that.
俺たちにも 責任の一端はある
By the way, it's not important,
but do you mind if I ask you something?
ところで つまんないこと聞いてもいいですか
What is it?
何だ
Were your glasses just for show?
眼鏡…ダテだったんですか
What?
I don't like how my face looks, especially my eyes.
自分の顔が嫌いでね
特に目元が…
But I don't care about that anymore, so it didn't seem to matter.
だがもう
どうでもよくなったんだ 今は…
The face of Division 1 sure has changed, hasn't it?
一係も様変わりしちゃったわよね
Shu, Masa, Shinya...
秀君に征さん 慎也君…
They're all gone.
みんないなくなっちゃった
It means that old-fashioned guys aren't suited for this job.
時代遅れな男たちには
この仕事は向いてないってこと
Isn't calling them old-fashioned a bit harsh?
時代遅れはひどいんじゃない
Why don't you call them romantics?
ロマンチストって言ってあげなよ
Do you think they might take comfort in that?
それで慰めになるのかしらね あいつら…
This is the Criminal Investigation
Department, part of the Public Safety Bureau.
こちらは公安局刑事課です
Access to this block is currently restricted to ensure safety.
現在 この区画は安全のために
立ち入りが制限されています
Excuse me!
あの 監視官の常守さんですか
Are you Inspector Tsunemori?
Yes.
ええ 配属早々に事件とは災難ね
You've got rotten luck, having to deal
with an incident right after getting posted.
I'm Shimotsuki Mika. I've been assigned to the CID as of today.
本日付で刑事課に配属になりました
霜月美佳です
Pleased to meet you!
よろしくお願いします
Sorry, but the CID is very short on manpower.
悪いけど
刑事課の人手不足は深刻なの
I'll do what I can to help, but you'll have to hit the ground running.
フォローはするけど 新米扱いはできない
I'm aware of that.
承知しています
I'm looking forward to the work.
望むところです
That's what I like to hear.
いい返事ね
That's...
あれは
The guys you're about to meet are humans just like us,
今から会う連中は
同じ人間ではあるけれど
but they'll deal with crimes using
criteria for judgment different from yours.
君とはまったく違う判断基準で犯罪に対処する
Their actions sometimes may be beyond your comprehension.
彼らの行動は
時として君の理解を超えたものになるかもしれない
Trust them, but at the same time, be cautious of them.
信頼する分だけ用心もしなさい
If you underestimate them, you'll get seriously hurt.
嘗めてかかると大ケガをする
They're what we call "Enforcers".
それが執行官
They'll be your subordinates.
君が預かる部下たちよ
Dominator Portable Psychological
Diagnosis and Suppression System
「携帯型心理診断」
「鎮圧執行システム·ドミネーター起動しました」
has been activated.
Dareka wo aisuru koto nante
There's no way I could love anyone,
誰かを愛することなんて
Dekiru wake nakutte
But I wish to be loved by someone in turn
できるわけなくって
The world may not have
Dakedo dareka ni aisaretakute
だけど誰かに愛されたくて
Kawaranai kinou ga zutto tsuzuita to shite mo
Ended yesterday after all,
変わらない昨日がずっと続いたとしても
But we will not budge
Doko ni mo ike ya shinainda
どこにも行けやしないんだ
From where we are
watashi to kimi
私とキミ
God, in favor of which parts have you left us?
Kamisama doko he itte shimatta no nee
神さま どこへ行ってしまったの ねえ
I receive no reply, I never do
Henji wa nakute itsu datte sou da yo
返事はなくて　いつだってそうだよ
I receive no reply, I never do
Henji wa nakute itsu datte sou da yo
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
I walk with you
Anata to iku
あなたと行く
Donna tsumi mo
I will share all your sins
どんな罪も
Seotte ageru
背負ってあげる
Together with you
Michi naki michi wo
道なき道を
I walk
Aruiteku no
歩いてくの
A trackless path
Anata to futari de
あなたと二人で
Swann's
Way
The chain of justice —
the system — never ends...